<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thomasnagel.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://thomasnagel.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2022-12-06T11:00:39+00:00</updated><id>https://thomasnagel.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tom’s page</title><subtitle>A website about Tom </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Doom 2016 vs Eternal</title><link href="https://thomasnagel.github.io/blog/2022/doom/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Doom 2016 vs Eternal"/><published>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://thomasnagel.github.io/blog/2022/doom</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thomasnagel.github.io/blog/2022/doom/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="origin">Origin</h2> <p>The Doom franchise is pretty old. Dating back to the first game, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doom_(1993_video_game)">Doom 1993</a>, published by ID Software in 1993. This was a revolutionary game. Mainly due to the impressive graphics it was able to produce on the limited hardware it was played on. While it wasn’t the first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First-person_shooter">FPS</a>, it was the first FPS where the player could move in 3 dimensions. However under the hood, the game engine did not make 3D calculations, because those were to resource intesive. The developers had to use some clever trickery to make the game look and feel like 3D.</p> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/Doom1993-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/Doom1993-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/Doom1993-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/Doom1993.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <div class="caption"> Doom 1993 </div> <hr/> <h2 id="doom-2016">Doom 2016</h2> <p>While <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doom_(2016_video_game)">this game</a> is not as legendary as it namesake, it is just as fun to play. Its ruthless <a href="https://music.youtube.com/playlist?list=OLAK5uy_kSfcuckNboAymIpsoq6hb1y5TvtyUU6p4">music</a> and brutal graphics make it a true masterpiece. This game redefined what it means to be a shooter. Classic mechanics like reloading and hiding to regenerate health are thrown out of the window. Instead of running away, the player is encouraged to charge headfirst into the frenzy by the glory kill system. This system rewards a player with health and armour after performing a glory kill. A glory kill can be performed on a heavily damaged enemy by hitting it with a melee attack.</p> <div class="tenor-gif-embed" data-postid="5455422" data-share-method="host" data-aspect-ratio="1.77778" data-width="100%"> <a href="https://tenor.com/view/doom-glory-kill-gif-5455422"> Doom Glory GIF </a> from <a href="https://tenor.com/search/doom-gifs"> Doom GIFs </a> </div> <script type="text/javascript" async="" src="https://tenor.com/embed.js"></script> <div class="caption"> Doom slayer performs glory kill on Hell knight </div> <hr/> <h2 id="doom-eternal">Doom Eternal</h2> <p>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doom_Eternal">latest game</a> in the Doom franchise. The developers truely doubled down on the style of arena combat that its predecessor, Doom 2016, invented. The new demons always force the player to stay moving. With the new mechanics, a dash and a grapple hook on the Super Shotgun, you become a raging fury that flies throught the arena. The high pased combat forces you to quickly make decisions on the fly.</p> <div class="tenor-gif-embed" data-postid="16068195" data-share-method="host" data-aspect-ratio="1.95122" data-width="100%"> <a href="https://tenor.com/view/seraphim-saber-doom-eternal-doomguy-doom-slayer-id-software-gif-16068195"> Seraphim Saber Doom Eternal GIF </a> from <a href="https://tenor.com/search/seraphim+saber-gifs"> Seraphim Saber GIFs </a> </div> <script type="text/javascript" async="" src="https://tenor.com/embed.js"></script> <div class="caption"> Doom Eternal gameplay </div> <hr/> <h2 id="comparison">Comparison</h2> <p>While both games are great to play, they do have some significant differences. 2016 has a very realistic artstyle. Eternal on the other hand has more ‘cartoony’ player and demon models, while also painting fast and grandious landscapes. Overall I would say that the demons in 2016 look far better then eternal.</p> <p>The combat in both games adhere to the same principles. Eternal however perfected the groundwork that 2016 layed. It feels somewhat slow to move around in 2016 after your used to the dashes and hooks in eternal.</p> <p>The overall story in 2016 is very down to earth (eventhough everything takes place on Mars and in Hell). Eternal introduces a lot of new lore about the Doom slayer. Everything takes place on a much grander scale. It turns out that the slayer is even mightier than God himself…</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Doom"/><category term="Game"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A discussion of the games Doom (2016) and Doom Eternal]]></summary></entry></feed>